<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on My Professional Website</title><link>https://nejads.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on My Professional Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 17:15:18 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nejads.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Key management service on AWS</title><link>https://nejads.github.io/blog/kms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 17:15:18 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nejads.github.io/blog/kms/</guid><description>In this post we will discuss what Key Management System is and what are the main features of it. Furthermore, we will show how you can integrate KMS with Aws Lambda and migrate your signing and verification workload to the KMS service. At last, we will discuss a limitation on creating CSRs in the KMS service and a solution for it using Bouncycastle and Java. 🚀
What is KMS service The key management service (KMS) is a service for the creation and management of the cryptographic keys.</description></item><item><title>Exploring Solidity Vulnerabilities: Risks and Best Practices for Secure Smart Contracts</title><link>https://nejads.github.io/blog/smart-contract/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 09:13:51 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nejads.github.io/blog/smart-contract/</guid><description>Definitions A blockchain is an append-only data structure which works on top of the peer-to-peer collection of nodes. Although Bitcoin is the most popular cryptocurrency and the most popular public ledger application, it has limited support for Smart contracts. The most famous framework for Smart contracts is Ethereum. [eth-smart-contract] A Smart contract is a computer program which a compiler can compile them to binary machine codes, written in a Turning-complete language like Solidity.</description></item><item><title>Import to Excel functionality in Spring framework</title><link>https://nejads.github.io/blog/excel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 13:42:51 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nejads.github.io/blog/excel/</guid><description>In this article we will see how to implement a back-end service in springboot applications to get some data in Excel format and serve it to the client. Generating huge excel file is CPU- and memory demanding. In other side, dependening on which version of excel will you generate, the file has limit e.g. Excel 2003 has max capacity on 65,535 rows. The chart below shows some facts about Excel file capacity.</description></item><item><title>Pagination in Spring Boot Applications</title><link>https://nejads.github.io/blog/pagination/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 10:10:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nejads.github.io/blog/pagination/</guid><description>Paging Paging in web applications is a mechanism to separate a big resultset to smaller chunks. Providing a fluent paging navigator could increase both the value of your website for search engines and enhance user experience through minimizing the response time. The famous example of paging is google&amp;rsquo;s search result page. Normally, the result page is separated into several pages. To avoid the bad user experience mentioned before, a lot of sites show only the current, the first, the last and some adjacent pages.</description></item><item><title>MQTT</title><link>https://nejads.github.io/blog/mqtt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 17:06:36 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nejads.github.io/blog/mqtt/</guid><description>The application development is a fast growing trend in the past few years. This, however, is not only associated with smartphones, tablets and smart-TV:s but with the automotive industry as well. The development of applications enhances human-vehicle interaction and provides a comprehensive overview of the vehicle and surroundings for the driver. The goal of this project is to increase the safety and security of the integration between external applications with the vehicle infotainment-system.</description></item></channel></rss>